MELHEM EL DIRANI

Frontend Web Developer

SUMMARY

Melhem is an experienced self-taught frontend web developer. He has extensive knowledge of JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js as well as significant experience with popular libraries and frameworks such as React.





Maximos st. Saida. Lebanon



melhemdirani@hotmail.com



https://melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/



+961 71 523 153

EXPERIENCE

Intern Frontend Web Developer, Sicilia mia

April 2021 to October 2021

- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Developing and implementing highly-responsive user interface components using React concepts.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows and frameworks like Redux.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

Web development team leader/CEO, Reboost 2021 to present

- Working closely with the coordination team to understand business requirements and help translate these into technical requirements for the development team
- Planning and documenting technical specifications for features or system design
- Designing, building and configuring applications to meet business process and application requirements
- Directing the development team in the design, development, coding, testing and debugging of applications
- Writing testable, scalable and efficient code and leading code reviews
- Mentoring junior team members and ensuring they adhere to determined software quality standards

Web development Teacher,

2021 to present

- Guide and assist fresh students in their study plan.
- each new concepts, languages and frameworks.
- Provide students with relevant resources.

COURSES

The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery - ZeroToMastery Academy

Complete React Developer in 2021 (w Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) - ZeroToMastery Academy

Front-End Web Development with React - Coursera

Javascript: The Advanced Concepts - ZeroToMastery Academy

Responsive Web Design FreeCodeCamp

EDUCATION

Master Degree in Civil Engineering Rafik Hariri University - 2018

Bachelor Degree in Civil Engineering University of Illinois, 2004 LANGUAGES

ARABIC - NATIVE ENGLISH - ADVANCED FRENCH - BEGINNER GERMAN - BEGINNER